<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Routing Loop</title>
    <description>Weekly AWS Networking Twitch Show</description>
    <link>/</link>
    <atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 13:06:14 -0800</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 13:06:14 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.3.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title><![CDATA[Bridging NetOps and CloudOps with Amazon VPC IPAM and Infoblox]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[18 February 2026 Bridging NetOps and CloudOps with Amazon VPC IPAM and Infoblox Hosts:Alex Huides Guests:Raunak Tibrewal, Sr. Product Manager, AWS Rishabh Parmar, Director of Product Management, Infoblox 📅 Add to Calendar Abstract:Managing IP addresses across hybrid environments doesn’t have to be painful. In this joint AWS and Infoblox session, we’ll show how integrating Infoblox Universal IPAM with Amazon VPC IPAM enables centralized visibility, automated allocation, and consistent governance across AWS and on-prem networks. Learn how customers are reducing manual effort, avoiding overlapping address space, and empowering both NetOps and CloudOps teams to move faster with confidence. Session hasn't started....]]></description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 11:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>/2026/02/18/ipam_and_infoblox.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2026/02/18/ipam_and_infoblox.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title><![CDATA[Secure Global DNS resolution: Introducing Route 53 Global Resolver]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[11 February 2026 Secure Global DNS resolution: Introducing Route 53 Global Resolver Hosts:Matt Lehwess Guests:Adhish Bhobe, Senior Product Manager, Route 53 📅 Add to Calendar Abstract:Join us to learn how Amazon Route 53 Global Resolver delivers secure, consistent, and globally available DNS resolution for distributed clients and hybrid environments. We’ll explore how this internet-reachable, anycast DNS resolver simplifies public and private domain resolution, enforces centralized security and threat filtering, supports encrypted DNS protocols, and reduces operational complexity and infrastructure overhead across remote offices, on-premises sites, and cloud workloads. Session hasn't started. Join live on 11 February 2026 at 11 AM...]]></description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 11:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>/2026/02/11/r53_global_resolver.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2026/02/11/r53_global_resolver.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title><![CDATA[re:Invent 2025 - Chalk Talk - Solving private IPv4 exhaustion using AWS Cloud WAN and Amazon VPC Lattice ]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[4 February 2026 re:Invent 2025 - Chalk Talk - Solving private IPv4 exhaustion using AWS Cloud WAN and Amazon VPC Lattice Hosts:Matt Lehwess Guests:Alexandra Huides, Pr. Solutions Architect Mehdi Dahan, Sr. Solutions Architect 📅 Add to Calendar Abstract:Enterprises face private IPv4 exhaustion due to limited address planning, architectural shifts, mergers, and IP-hungry technologies like containers. The result - restrictions to cloud scalability and new project deployment. In this session, learn how AWS solutions solve these challenges with a scalable and cost effective approach combining AWS Cloud WAN with service insertion, and Amazon VPC Lattice to centralize private NAT Gateways and...]]></description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 11:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>/2026/02/04/chalk_talk_lattice.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2026/02/04/chalk_talk_lattice.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title><![CDATA[re:Invent 2025 - Chalk Talk - I didn't know AWS WAF did this]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[28 January 2026 re:Invent 2025 - Chalk Talk - I didn't know AWS WAF did this Hosts:Tom Adamski Guests:Kartik Bheemisetty, Technical Account Manager, AWS 📅 Add to Calendar Abstract:Think AWS WAF is just for blocking SQL injection and XSS? Think again. In this interactive chalk talk, we'll dive into creative, real-world use cases - from deploying honeypots and shedding traffic, to stopping account fraud and mitigating DDoS at scale. We'll explore advanced configurations, walk through customer-tested patterns, and whiteboard strategies that make WAF a powerful tool in your security arsenal. Bring your questions and experiences - we're here to break...]]></description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 11:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>/2026/01/28/chalk_talk_waf.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2026/01/28/chalk_talk_waf.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title><![CDATA[re:Invent 2025 - Chalk Talk - Origin management for multi-region applications with Amazon CloudFront ]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[21 January 2026 re:Invent 2025 - Chalk Talk - Origin management for multi-region applications with Amazon CloudFront Hosts:Jamie Wenzel Guests:Vinicius Pedroni, Sr. Solutions Architect Jonathan Woods, Solutions Architect 📅 Add to Calendar Abstract:In this session, you'll learn comprehensive origin management with Amazon CloudFront to build secure, resilient content delivery systems. We will cover automatic failover mechanisms with CloudFront and Route53, configure granular origin routing with CloudFront Functions, and secure origins using S3 with Origin Access Control (OAC) and VPC private origins for enhanced security. We'll explore integrating on-premises infrastructure through AWS Direct Connect for hybrid architectures, and deploy Origin Shield...]]></description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 11:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>/2026/01/21/chalk_talk_CloudFront_origin_management.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2026/01/21/chalk_talk_CloudFront_origin_management.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title><![CDATA[All AWS Networking launches from re:Invent - Recap & Q&A]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[14 January 2026 All AWS Networking launches from re:Invent - Recap &amp; Q&amp;A Hosts:Alexandra Huides, Tom Adamski Guests: 📅 Add to Calendar Abstract:We shipped a lot of new AWS networking capabilities at and before re:Invent 2025 - and we’re breaking them all down, live. Join The Routing Loop for a rapid walkthrough of every major Networking &amp; Content Delivery launch from re:Invent, what changed, why it matters, and how you can actually use it. This session is fully interactive: bring your questions, challenge assumptions, and ask how these launches fit into real-world architectures. If you missed re:Invent, felt overwhelmed by...]]></description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 11:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>/2026/01/14/riv_recap.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2026/01/14/riv_recap.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title><![CDATA[The Routing Loop: Intro to Cloud WAN Advanced Routing]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[

  7 January 2026

  The Routing Loop: Intro to Cloud WAN Advanced Routing

  Hosts:Matt Lehwess, Sidhartha Chauhan
  Guests:
  
    📅 
          Add to Calendar
       
  
  
    Abstract:Managing a global network shouldn't mean losing control over your traffic. In this episode of The Routing Loop, we're introducing the latest routing enhancements for AWS Cloud WAN. We'll explore how new policy-driven features give you more precision over how routes move across your global core network.
  

  
  
     
    
      
    
    
    Session Feedback/Content Suggestions
  

  

]]></description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 11:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>/2026/01/07/cloud_wan_routing_policy.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2026/01/07/cloud_wan_routing_policy.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title><![CDATA[New Launch - Network Firewall Proxy Walkthrough]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[10 December 2025 New Launch - Network Firewall Proxy Walkthrough Hosts:Tom Adamski Guests: 📅 Add to Calendar Abstract:Join us for our final Twitch session of 2025, where we’ll dive into the newly launched AWS Network Firewall Proxy. We’ll whiteboard, chat, and demo the feature to show how it enables centralized controls against data exfiltration and malware injection, with simple setup in explicit mode. Network Firewall Proxy helps you efficiently secure web and inter-network traffic by protecting against domain name and SNI spoofing, enforcing fine-grained access controls, and restricting application traffic to trusted domains or IPs while blocking unintended external responses....]]></description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 11:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>/2025/12/10/nfw_proxy.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2025/12/10/nfw_proxy.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title><![CDATA[re:Invent 2025 - Know before you go]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[

  19 November 2025

  re:Invent 2025 - Know before you go

  Hosts:Alexandra Huides, Jamie Wenzel
  Guests:Anusha Jampala, Sr Product Marketing Manager
  
    📅 
          Add to Calendar
       
  
  
    Abstract:Learn about what's happening in the Networking track at re:Invent 2025
  

  
  
     
    
      
    
    
    Session Feedback/Content Suggestions
  

  

]]></description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 11:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>/2025/11/19/riv_know_b4_u_go.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2025/11/19/riv_know_b4_u_go.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title><![CDATA[New Launch -  Amazon VPC Lattice support for custom DNS for resources]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[12 November 2025 New Launch - Amazon VPC Lattice support for custom DNS for resources Hosts:Alexandra Huides, Matt Lehwess Guests:Mohak Kohli, Sr. SDE, VPC Lattice 📅 Add to Calendar Abstract:In this video, we explore a new VPC Lattice enhancement that lets you attach custom domain names to your resource configurations. This update expands how teams expose and access layer-4 resources—such as databases, clusters, and internal domains—across VPCs and AWS accounts. With this release, resource owners can assign a custom domain to a resource configuration and share it with consumers, who can then access the resource through that domain. VPC Lattice...]]></description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 11:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>/2025/11/12/custom_dns_lattice_resources.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2025/11/12/custom_dns_lattice_resources.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title><![CDATA[Let s chat AWS networking with Jamie and Matt]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[

  5 November 2025

  Let s chat AWS networking with Jamie and Matt

  Hosts:Jamie Wenzel, Matt Lehwess
  Guests:
  
    📅 
          Add to Calendar
       
  
  
    Abstract:Open discussion on AWS networking with Jamie and Matt
  

  
  
     
    
      
    
    
    Session Feedback/Content Suggestions
  

  

]]></description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 11:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>/2025/11/05/Jamie-&amp;-Matt-Discsusion.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2025/11/05/Jamie-&amp;-Matt-Discsusion.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title><![CDATA[To do or not to do VPC Sharing: A candid chat about VPC sharing considerations and best practices]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[29 October 2025 To do or not to do VPC Sharing: A candid chat about VPC sharing considerations and best practices Hosts:Alexandra Huides, Matt Lehwess Guests: 📅 Add to Calendar Abstract:VPC sharing can be a powerful way to simplify network management and enable teams to collaborate securely — but it’s not a one-size-fits-all solution. In this episode of The Routing Loop, we’re having a candid chat about when (and when not) to use Amazon VPC sharing. We’ll unpack real-world pros and cons, from operational efficiency and security boundaries to service ownership, scaling, and governance. Whether you’re a platform team debating...]]></description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>/2025/10/29/vpc_sharing.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2025/10/29/vpc_sharing.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title><![CDATA[Amazon VPC and dynamic routing with VPC Route Server]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[

  22 October 2025

  Amazon VPC and dynamic routing with VPC Route Server

  Hosts:Jamie Wenzel
  Guests:Ammar Latif, Pr. Solutions Architect, Telco, AWS 
  
    📅 
          Add to Calendar
       
  
  
    Abstract:Join us as we explore how AWS Route Server brings dynamic routing to Amazon VPC. See how it enables BGP route exchange between your virtual appliances and AWS networking services, making it easier to build scalable, automated, and flexible cloud networks.
  

  
  
     
    
      
    
    
    Session Feedback/Content Suggestions
  

  

]]></description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>/2025/10/22/route_server.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2025/10/22/route_server.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title><![CDATA[Route 53 Resolver endpoint delegation]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[

  15 October 2025

  Route 53 Resolver endpoint delegation

  Hosts:Tom Adamski
  Guests:Tekena Orugbani, Sr. Solutions Architect, AWS  Adhish Bhobe, Sr. Product Manager, Route 53, AWS 
  
    📅 
          Add to Calendar
       
  
  
    Abstract:A new capability of Route 53 Resolver endpoints, that helps customers make delegations for private hosted zone subdomains using Route 53 inbound and outbound Resolver endpoints. The feature allows customers to delegate the authority for a subdomain from their on-premises infrastructure to the Route 53 Resolver cloud service and vice versa, enabling a simplified cloud experience across namespaces in AWS and on their own local infrastructure.
  

  
  
     
    
      
    
    
    Session Feedback/Content Suggestions
  

  

]]></description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>/2025/10/15/resolver_delegation.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2025/10/15/resolver_delegation.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title><![CDATA[Modern Connectivity Patterns for ISVs on AWS]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[

  8 October 2025

  Modern Connectivity Patterns for ISVs on AWS

  Hosts:Alexandra Huides, Tom Adamski
  Guests:
  
    📅 
          Add to Calendar
       
  
  
    Abstract:How do Independent Software Vendors build secure, scalable connectivity with their customers on AWS? In this session, we’ll unpack common networking patterns ISVs use to expose their applications to end customers — and how they gain access to customer-owned data sources in the reverse direction. We’ll compare public connectivity approaches with private networking options, from VPC peering and Transit Gateway to application-centric services like AWS PrivateLink and Amazon VPC Lattice.
  

  
  
     
    
      
    
    
    Session Feedback/Content Suggestions
  

  

]]></description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>/2025/10/08/isv_connectivity.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2025/10/08/isv_connectivity.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title><![CDATA[Load Balancer Capacity Units - What are they? Why do I care]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[

  1 October 2025

  Load Balancer Capacity Units - What are they? Why do I care

  Hosts:Jamie Wenzel
  Guests:Hema Halagatti, Sr. Product Manager, Load Balancing, AWS  Jon Zobrist, Head of ELB Customer Success, AWS 
  
    📅 
          Add to Calendar
       
  
  
    Abstract:Load Balancer Capacity Units can feel a little mysterious. Fear not, we’ve got you covered. In this session, we’ll break down what they are, how you can reserve them, and practical ways to keep your costs under control. Join us for a clear, no-nonsense look at making LCU management simple and cost-effective.
  

  
  
     
    
      
    
    
    Session Feedback/Content Suggestions
  

  

]]></description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>/2025/10/01/lcus_walkthrough.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2025/10/01/lcus_walkthrough.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title><![CDATA[Using generative AI for building AWS networks]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[24 September 2025 Using generative AI for building AWS networks Hosts:Sidhartha Chauhan Guests:Sohaib Tahir, Principal Solutions Architect, AWS 📅 Add to Calendar Abstract:Join us for a deep dive into the transformative potential of generative AI in building and managing AWS networks. This webinar will explore how tools like Amazon Bedrock and Amazon Q can streamline complex network tasks, from initial greenfield deployments to network migration and modernization. We'll demonstrate practical use cases, including using natural language prompts to deploy a global network with AWS Cloud WAN, updating policies, and generating infrastructure as code (IaC) templates. Learn how to accelerate your...]]></description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>/2025/09/24/build_net_with_ai.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2025/09/24/build_net_with_ai.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title><![CDATA[Finding Network Root Causes in Seconds with Digital Twins and Agentic AI]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[

  17 September 2025

  Finding Network Root Causes in Seconds with Digital Twins and Agentic AI

  Hosts:Matt Lehwess, Jamie Wenzel
  Guests:Imen GRIDA BEN YAHYA, Principal Solutions Architect, Telecom AI/ML, AWS 
  
    📅 
          Add to Calendar
       
  
  
    Abstract:Network failures can often take hours to diagnose. This week on The Routing Loop, we'll show how a network digital twin with graph DB and Agentic AI can find root causes in seconds. Join Jamie, Matt, and Imen for a deep dive into making network operations faster and more reliable.
  

  
  
     
    
      
    
    
    Session Feedback/Content Suggestions
  

  

]]></description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>/2025/09/17/root_cause_with_ai.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2025/09/17/root_cause_with_ai.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title><![CDATA[Uncover network security issues with AWS Shield network security director]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[

  10 September 2025

  Uncover network security issues with AWS Shield network security director

  Hosts:Tom Adamski
  Guests:Neil Yajnik, Sr. Product Manager, AWS 
  
    📅 
          Add to Calendar
       
  
  
    Abstract:Discover how Shield's Network Security Director transforms network security management. Watch live demonstrations of network topology visualization, security assessment, and AI-assisted investigation. Learn best practices for strengthening your security posture and get your questions answered by AWS experts.
  

  
  
     
    
      
    
    
    Session Feedback/Content Suggestions
  

  

]]></description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>/2025/09/10/net_security_director.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2025/09/10/net_security_director.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title><![CDATA[AWS Network Observability: Deep Dive into Network Reachability and Access Analyzer]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[3 September 2025 AWS Network Observability: Deep Dive into Network Reachability and Access Analyzer Hosts:Sidhartha Chauhan Guests:Ankit Chadha, Principal Solutions Architect, Networking 📅 Add to Calendar Abstract:This comprehensive 60-minute webinar explores the powerful combination of AWS Network Reachability Analyzer and Network Access Analyzer for improving both network observability and security. Ideal for cloud architects, DevOps engineers, and security professionals, this session will guide you through the why and when of using these tools, with a primary focus on end-to-end observability use cases that also enhance security.We'll begin with a brief introduction to these analyzers, then delve into real-world scenarios showcasing...]]></description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2025 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>/2025/09/03/reachablity_and_access_analyzer.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2025/09/03/reachablity_and_access_analyzer.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
